{
  "reference_number": "1545",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The answers are heavily biased and not giving objective enough definitions. The government needs to better research and\n\n implement or fund to quicker implement alternatives uses of technology before banning and upheaving current methods of practise.\n Give us better access to a better way system or materials and infrastructure and we will organically take it up enmass don't punish us\n by taxation for simply existing with no reasonable alternative systems readily available"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Stop giving us leading questions don't set a net zero target by 2050"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "This is bulshit, forestry is only a temporary carbon soak, eventually the trees die and decay releasing the carbon again and buying\n carbon credits achieves nothing except making another country rich"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Our only hope is the next government flushing this turd of an idea down the toilet"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "We will never see a change in the global environment from our efforts and we will waste millions or billions on it further destroying our\n economy we should be focusing on cleaning our local environment until more larger countries are prepared to cooperate and fight\n\n this collectively"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "This should not be set at all as it will achieve nothing except raise or costs of living and inflation even more than this government\n already is we can only prey the next government puts it out with the trash"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The government should not be setting unrealistic expensive pointless emissions goals"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "I haven't read them but I guarantee they are idealistic un reasonable not practical expensive and will ultimately achieve nothing. Our\ncountries population makes up 0.055% of the global population so any efforts we make alone will be futile"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "No because it will achieve nothing we should set our sights on cleaning up our local environment before tackling an impossible task\nlike single handed altering the global climate"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "You need to consider the reality of what you will achieve and how much it is going to impact on our economy, when and by how much\n\ncan you prove beyond reasonable doubt any of these hairbrained ideas will show significant success"
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The climate change commission is a fraud a waste of money and should be disbanded"
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The emissions trading scheme is a scam and a fraud and we should have nothing to do with it"
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The only expertise the climate change has is fooling you into buying what it's selling and it's preparing to take you for the ride of your\n\nlives"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Before we spend money we need proof what we are planning to do will have A measurable effect on the global environment"
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Climate change is a natural phenomenon and we are incredibly arrogant to think we can have that much effect on it especially NZs\n\n0.055% of the global population"
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Stop spending money on something that will achieve no measurable outcome, the Hawaii volcano is doing more \"harm\" to the\n\nenvironment than this scam of a scheme could hope to undo in several life times"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Anthropogenic climate change is a sham and we can't. Alter the global climate without massive cooperation from many much larger\n\ncountries we dont have to be the leaders at everything especially not spending time and money pushing the proverbially up hill to\naccomplish nothing significant! Don't set emission targets until we can measure the benefit of doing so or fund cleaner alternatives\n\nso we organically move to them more quickly and the larger scale of use will also bring the costs diwn"
    }
  ]
}
